how the Holy Spirit works in the soul.
كيف يعمل الروح القدس في النفس.
Running all the way from His effectual calling,
فراراً من دعوته الفعالة ،
and regeneration,
والتجديد ،
all the way to glorification.
وصولا إلى التمجيد.
So it's a very important subject
لذلك فهو موضوع مهم للغاية
and I'm glad you're with me.
وأنا سعيد لأنك معي.
We're going to look at it in some detail.
سوف ننظر في الأمر بشيء من التفصيل.
I think you'll enjoy the class.
أعتقد أنك ستستمتع بالفصل.
After all,
بعد كل شيء،
all of our
كل منا
Christianity,
النصرانية،
all of our personal religion
كل ديننا الشخصي
is just a sham without the Holy Spirit.
مجرد خدعة بدون الروح القدس.
So we're very,
لذلك نحن جدا ،
very grateful for the ministry of the Holy Spirit,
ممتن جدا لخدمة الروح القدس ،
I want to begin this
أريد أن أبدأ هذا
first lecture with the reading of God's word,
المحاضرة الأولى بقراءة كلمة الله ،
as we will with each each lecture. Turn with me, please, to Romans 8 and I'll read 13 through 17. Romans 8: 13 through 17.
كما نفعل مع كل محاضرة. استدر معي ، من فضلك، إلى رومية 8 وسأقرأ من 13 إلى 17. رومية 8: 13 حتى 17.
For,
إلى عن على،
if you live after the flesh,
إذا كنت تعيش بعد الجسد ،
you shall die.
تموت.
But if ye
ولكن إذا كنتم
through the Spirit do mortify,
من خلال الروح تميت ،
the deeds of the body
أفعال الجسد
ye shall live.
ستعيشون.
For as many as are led
لكثير من الذين يقودون
by the Spirit of God,
بروح الله
they are the sons of God.
هم ابناء الله.
For you have not received the Spirit
لأنك لم تقبل الروح
of bondage again to fear,
من العبودية مرة أخرى للخوف ،
but you have received the Spirit of adoption
ولكنك قد قبلت روح التبني
whereby we cry Abba,
حيث نبكي أبا ،
Father.
أب.
The Spirit itself beareth witness with our spirit
الروح نفسه يشهد لأرواحنا
that we are the children of God,
أننا أبناء الله ،
and if children then heirs,
وإذا كان الأبناء ثم الورثة ،
heirs of God and joint heirs with Christ.
ورثة الله ووارثون مشتركون مع المسيح.
If so be
إذا كان الأمر كذلك
that we suffer with him,
التي نعانيها معه ،
that we may also be glorified together. Let's seek God's face in prayer. Lord God, we stand on holy ground,
حتى نتمجد ايضا معا. دعونا نطلب وجه الله في الصلاة. ربنا يارب نقف على أرض مقدسة ،
as we approach this
ونحن نقترب من هذا
immense subject of the third person of the Holy Trinity
موضوع هائل للشخص الثالث من الثالوث الأقدس
and his salvific work in our souls.
وعمله الخلاصي في نفوسنا.
And we do pray that
ونحن نصلي ذلك
by the end of this course,
بنهاية هذه الدورة ،
we will have a much more profound appreciation
سيكون لدينا تقدير أكثر عمقا
for the saving ministry of the Holy Spirit,
لخدمة الروح القدس الخلاصي ،
than we perhaps might have at present
مما قد يكون لدينا في الوقت الحاضر
Help us to grow,
ساعدنا على النمو ،
not only in the grace and knowledge of Jesus,
ليس فقط بنعمة يسوع ومعرفته ،
whom the Spirit focuses upon,
الذي يركز عليه الروح ،
but also that we would grow
ولكن أيضًا أننا سننمو
in the grace and knowledge of the Holy Spirit,
بنعمة الروح القدس ومعرفته ،
becoming more aware of His work,
أن يصبح أكثر وعياً بعمله ،
His saving work,
عمله الخلاصي ،
and appreciating more profoundly the vastness of His ministry as he works in sinners and rebels, such as we all are by nature. So Lord bless this class.
وتقدير أكثر عمقا اتساع خدمته كما يعمل في الخطاة والمتمردين ، مثلنا جميعًا بطبيعتنا. لذلك بارك الرب هذا الفصل.
Help me in teaching.
ساعدني في التدريس.
Help the students in listening,
مساعدة الطلاب في الاستماع ،
learning,
التعلم،
and grant that each lecture
وامنح ان كل محاضرة
may serve to thy glory,
قد يخدم مجدك ،
to our spiritual growth,
لنمونا الروحي ،
and to the well-being
والرفاهية
of our entire being as we journey
من كياننا بأكمله أثناء رحلتنا
to the never-ending eternity.
إلى الأبدية التي لا تنتهي.
Be with us now we pray.
كن معنا الآن نصلي.
In Jesus name.
باسم يسوع.
Amen.
آمين.
Well,
نحن سوف،
thank you for joining us for this class
شكرا لانضمامك إلينا في هذا الفصل
and I want to
وانا اريد ان
begin with the first lecture,
تبدأ بالمحاضرة الأولى ،
which is titled: The Study
وهي الدراسة
of the Holy Spirit.
من الروح القدس.
The Study of the Holy Spirit. God's Holy spirit was with God's people from the beginning. Already in Genesis 1, verse 2
دراسة الروح القدس. كان روح الله القدوس مع شعب الله منذ البداية. بالفعل في تكوين 1 ، الآية 2
leading them ultimately to their rest
يقودهم في النهاية إلى راحتهم
in Jesus Christ (Isaiah 63 14)
في يسوع المسيح (إشعياء 63 14)
To know the Spirit
لمعرفة الروح
therefore is to stand in continuity
لذلك هو الوقوف في الاستمرارية
with the Saints of all ages.
مع القديسين من جميع الأعمار.
God has promised,
وعد الله ،
his Spirit already to Israel,
روحه بالفعل لإسرائيل ،
His chosen people.
شعبه المختار.
We know that in the Old Testament,
نحن نعلم أنه في العهد القديم ،
various individuals experience a comfort of that Spirit.
العديد من الأفراد يختبرون راحة ذلك الروح.
Think of David,
فكر في ديفيد ،
for example (Psalm 51)
على سبيل المثال (مزمور 51)
But God promised
لكن الله وعد
a far richer and broader work of the Spirit than we might possibly imagine. Isaiah foretold of a righteous king whose administration would be like,
عمل الروح أغنى وأوسع مما قد نتخيله. انبأ اشعياء بملك بار إدارته ستكون مثل ،
rivers of waters in a dry place
أنهار المياه في مكان جاف
and the transformation of the barren wilderness
وتحول البرية القاحلة
into a world filled with the fruit of righteousness (Isaiah 32).
إلى عالم مليء بثمار البر (إشعياء 32).
When the Spirit,
عندما الروح ،
When the Spirit
عندما الروح
is poured out upon us from on high.
يسكب علينا من العلاء.
And then he goes on to say in Isaiah 44,
ثم يذهب ليقول في إشعياء 44 ،
that the Spirit would be poured out on Israel,
حتى ينسكب الروح على إسرائيل ،
like a river
مثل النهر
of water on dry ground,
من الماء على الأرض الجافة ،
irrigating faithless souls to produce a people
سقي النفوس الكافرة لإنتاج الناس
who say I am the Lord's.
من يقول اني للرب.
And so the Spirit
وكذلك الروح
is the answer of God's covenantal faithfulness
هو جواب أمانة الله في العهد
to the chronic problem of Israel's covenant breaking. You find that also in the Book of Joel that the Lord would pour out his Spirit upon all his people
للمشكلة المزمنة من كسر عهد إسرائيل. تجد ذلك أيضًا في كتاب يوئيل أن يسكب الرب روحه على كل شعبه
that whosoever would call on the name
أن من ينادي بالاسم
of the Lord would be saved
من الرب سيخلص
(Joel 2:28 to 32).
(يوئيل 2:28 إلى 32).
So to study the work of the Holy Spirit
لذا لدراسة عمل الروح القدس
is to study heavenly work,
هو دراسة العمل السماوي ،
saving work.
إنقاذ العمل.
And work that abides forever.
والعمل الذي يبقى إلى الأبد.
Now,
حاليا،
of course,
بالطبع،
in the New Testament age you know,
في عصر العهد الجديد كما تعلم ،
that when Jesus rose from the dead
أنه عندما قام يسوع من بين الأموات
and ascended into heaven,
وصعد إلى الجنة
He poured out His Spirit
سكب روحه
in much larger measures than
بمقاييس أكبر بكثير من
had previously been known
كان معروفا من قبل
(Acts 2 17,
(أعمال 2 17 ،
through 21 and 33 and 34) And Peter after his sermon is interrupted by thousands of people who are under great conviction of sin.
من خلال 21 و 33 و 34) وانقطع بطرس بعد خطبته الآلاف من الناس الذين تحت تبكيت عظيم على الخطيئة.
Under it
تحته
and they cried out men and Brethren.
فصرخوا رجالا واخوة.
What shall we do?
ماذا عسانا نفعل؟
Peter said to them,
قال لهم بطرس:
repent and be baptized everyone of you
توبوا وليعتمدوا جميعكم
in the name of Jesus Christ.
باسم يسوع المسيح.
And you shall receive the gift of the Holy Ghost.
وتنال عطية الروح القدس.
For the promise is unto you
لان الوعد لكم
and to your children
ولأطفالك
and to all that are afar off.
ولكل ما هو بعيد.
Even as many as the Lord,
حتى كل من الرب ،
Our God shall call (Acts 2: 38 and 39).
سيدعو إلهنا (أعمال الرسل 2: 38 و 39).
And so the rest
وهكذا الباقي
of the New Testament writings,
من كتابات العهد الجديد ،
particularly Paul's Epistles,
ولا سيما رسائل بولس ،
are just filled with the Holy Spirit.
فقط من الروح القدس.
He speaks often
يتحدث كثيرا
about being born
عن ولادتهم
of the Spirit such as Galatians,
من الروح مثل غلاطية ،
4: 29.
4:29.
And he's talking constantly about different aspects of the Spirit's saving work. Like we just read a few of them to you from from Romans 8. So if we treasure Christ as our only mediator,
وهو يتحدث باستمرار حول الجوانب المختلفة لعمل خلاص الروح. كما قرأنا فقط القليل منهم من رومية 8. لذلك إذا كنا نعتز بالمسيح باعتباره الوسيط الوحيد لدينا ،
we will also treasure the Holy Spirit
سوف نعتز أيضًا بالروح القدس
as Christ's great gift,
كهدية المسيح العظيمة ،
which is inseparable from Him,
الذي لا ينفصل عنه ،
to sinners (John 4
للخطاة (يوحنا 4
and again John 7).
ومرة أخرى يوحنا 7).
Jonathan Edwards put it this way.
وضع جوناثان إدواردز الأمر بهذه الطريقة.
"The sum of the blessings Christ sought
"مجموع البركات التي طلبها المسيح
by what he did and suffered
بما فعله وعانى
in the work of redemption,
في عمل الفداء ،
was the Holy Spirit,
كان الروح القدس ،
the Holy Spirit in His indwelling,
الروح القدس في سكنه ،
His influences and fruits
تأثيراته وثماره
is the sum of all grace,
هو مجموع كل نعمة ،
holiness,
قداسة،
comfort and joy,
الراحة والفرح ،
or in one word
أو في كلمة واحدة
of all the spiritual good Christ purchased
من كل خير روحي اقتناها المسيح
for men in this world.
للرجال في هذا العالم.
And is also the sum of all perfection,
وهو أيضًا مجموع كل كمال ،
glory,
مجد،
and eternal joy, that he purchased for them in another world." That's an amazing quote by Edwards. And it certainly shows us
والفرح الأبدي ، الذي اشتراه لهم في عالم آخر ". هذا اقتباس رائع من إدواردز. وهذا يظهر لنا بالتأكيد
that many today are minimizing
التي يقوم الكثيرون بتقليلها اليوم
the role of the ministry
دور الوزارة
of the Holy Spirit as
من الروح القدس
integral with the entire
متكامل مع الكل
sum of blessings
مجموع النعم
that God's people receive in salvation.
التي ينالها شعب الله في الخلاص.
John Brown of Headington
جون براون من هيدينغتون
put it this way,
ضعها بهذه الطريقة،
"Did Christ purchase the Holy Spirit?
"هل اقتنى المسيح الروح القدس؟
Christ purchased the Spirit's gifts,
اشترى المسيح مواهب الروح ،
and influences in applying redemption,
وتأثيرات في تطبيق الفداء ،
but not his being,
ولكن ليس كيانه ،
which is independent."
وهو مستقل ".
So the work of the Spirit
هكذا عمل الروح
in many ways
بطرق عدة
is the fruit
هي الفاكهة
of Christ's death and resurrection.
عن موت المسيح وقيامته.
Now,
حاليا،
salvation in Christ
الخلاص في المسيح
is appreciated and enjoyed therefore only by knowing the Holy Spirit and his saving work. And this is one of the greatest doctrines of the Reformation,
هو موضع تقدير والاستمتاع لذلك فقط بمعرفة الروح القدس وعمله المنقذ. وهذه واحدة من أعظم مذاهب الإصلاح ،
developed so thoroughly and then even
تم تطويره بدقة ثم حتى
augmented by the Puritans.
عززها المتشددون.
What a treasure Reformed theology brings us
يا له من كنز يجلبه لنا علم اللاهوت المصلح
about the saving ministry of the Holy Spirit.
حول خدمة خلاص الروح القدس.
In fact,
في الواقع،
BB Warfield called John Calvin
دعا BB Warfield جون كالفين
The Theologian of the Holy Spirit.
لاهوتي الروح القدس.
And Warfield went on to claim
واستمر وارفيلد في المطالبة
the developed doctrine
العقيدة المتطورة
of the work of the Holy Spirit
من عمل الروح القدس
is an exclusively Reformation doctrine,
هي عقيدة الإصلاح حصريًا ،
and more particularly a Reformed doctrine,
وعلى وجه الخصوص العقيدة الإصلاحية ،
and still more particularly a Puritan doctrine.
ولا يزال على وجه الخصوص عقيدة بيوريتانية.
And so,
وهكذا،
study of the Spirit
دراسة الروح
through Reformed experiential soteriology,
من خلال علم الخلاص التجريبي المُصلح ،
- that is,
- هذا هو،
salvation that we experience by the work of the Spirit in the soul - opens up a vast wealth of wisdom and joy to the believer.
الخلاص الذي نختبره من خلال العمل للروح في الروح - يفتح ثروة هائلة من الحكمة والفرح للمؤمن.